## **Robert McKee**

Austin, TX (512) 203-5360

Rmckee8@gmail.com www.robertcmckee.com github.com/RCmckee linkedin.com/in/RobertCMcKee

Google Certified TensorFlow Developer with 2 years of experience applying machine learning to large datasets. 7+ years working with startups and Fortune 500 companies to analyze trends and discover business solutions.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

- Languages: Python, SQL, BASH, HTML/CSS.
- Frameworks/Libraries: TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, Pandas, NumPy, PyTorch, pyLDAvis, Flask, NLTK, selenium
- Artificial Intelligence (AI): Machine learning (Supervised learning, Regression, Multi-arm bandit, Decision trees, Random forest, Boosting, SVM, Network graphs), Cross validation, Regularization, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Deep Learning (DL), Keras.
- Data Visualization: matplotlib, seaborn, Tableau, LIME, SHAP, Google Data Studio, plotly.
- Databases and Cloud Computing: SQL (Postgres, Google BigQuery), NoSQL (MongoDB, PyMongo), Distributed system (Hadoop MapReduce), Cluster computing (Apache Spark, Pyspark), Cloud computing (AWS EC2), Version control (Git), BigQuery, AWS, Google Cloud Platform (GCP).
- Math and Statistics: Hypothesis testing and A/B testing (sampling and distribution).

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Hello World Studio, Austin, TX

June 2019 - Present

#### Data Science / Artificial Intelligence Instructor (Part-Time)

- Teach Python and Artificial Intelligence elements to middle school and high school classes of 10-50 students.
- Help students gain experience with data modeling and scientific computing through Data Science projects.

## Komply, Austin, TX **Data Science / NLP Intern**

**June 2019 - September 2019** 

- Performed NLP and text analytics for millions of legal documents using Python, SQL, and Jupyter notebooks.
- Built sentence classification models and metrics to analyze pipeline processing of documents as well as performed non-parametric analyses of text features using NLP to find useful insights.
- Worked closely with the CEO to determine the business and technical requirements for a sentence classification model that would assist in document analysis and finding errors.
- Utilized Datatiku, SQL, and Python to create an automated weekly email update that paired a fluid database with a data pipeline after reviewing SQL queries and incorporating user feedback to build new visualizations with the desired information, which resulted in the discovery of a pipeline that had been malfunctioning for 3 months.
- Deployed Machine Learning algorithms as APIs for use across the Engineering and Data Science teams.

# McKee PLLC, Austin, TX

September 2016 - September 2019

# **Attorney**

- Provided IP counseling and support for AI patent applications and trademark filings to companies.
- Used NLP methods to build classification models and also SQL to search through millions of legal documents.
- Built tools with Python to automatically create and file trademark applications through government websites, draft high-quality patent applications, and provide informed legal advice.
- Utilized SQL and Python for topic modeling to provide clients with a data-driven patent protection strategy.
- Performed web scraping, created SQL queries, and developed Python scripts to automate legal tasks for lawyers.

#### G51 Capital, Austin, TX **Venture Scholar**

June 2015 - January 2016

- Reviewed 100+ startup pitches, analyzed market trends, and advised partners on investment opportunities.
- Initiated contact with startups and transformed relationships into project work with Fortune 500 clients.
- Presented summaries of investment opportunities to Venture Capital partners and clients.

#### Kiverdi, San Francisco, CA Attornev

January 2013 - September 2014

- Grew the patent portfolio in size by three by identifying new innovations and writing patent applications, resulting in 35 US and international applications.
- Compiled and presented market reports validating the size of potential markets to determine successful business partnerships which resulted in a \$3.5M grant.
- Reduced the time required to generate, negotiate, and finalize over 100 nondisclosure agreements and 20 technology licensing agreements by over 75%.
- Led research within the company of 10 employees and worked directly with the CEO and Scientists.
- Built IP protection strategies, managed internal and external patent counsel, worked with Engineering and business teams to gather items to be included in patent applications, and determined which lab work would be required.
- Sourced new innovation leads, compiled patent applications, and initiated follow-up experiments to create supporting evidence necessary for strong patents.

# QB3, San Francisco, CA

August 2012 - November 2012

- **Post Graduate Fellow**
- Worked for UCSF's startup incubator and venture capital fund for life sciences and biotech companies.
- Handled the setup of Salesforce for startups as well as the initial training.
- Partnered with startups to decipher legal requirements, consult on which policies and procedures were to be followed based on location, and handled commercial leasing documents.

# The Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, TX Legal Intern

**January 2011 - April 2011** 

• Drafted a 100-page IT policies and procedures manual as well as loan, licensing, and purchasing agreements.

## Bankers Capital, Austin, TX

May 2007 - August 2008

#### Real Estate Analyst and Business Plan Intern

- Underwrote a \$510K SBA loan during the collapse of the lending market.
- Analyzed financial statements and business plans to determine the strength of the loan.
- Utilized Excel to gather cash flow projections and assets to create business plans.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS:**

TensorFlow Certified Developer: Google Developers Certification

Certified International Privacy Professional: US, iapp.org

#### **EDUCATION:**

Galvanize: Data Science Immersive, Project Topic: Document Classification, 2018

Python, Flask, Heroku, SQL, Hadoop, Spark, NLP, image recognition, text analysis, classification, and linear regression

The University of Texas at Austin: M.S., Technology Commercialization, 2016

The University of Houston Law Center: J.D., 2012

The University of Texas at Austin: B.S., Microbiology, 2007